Guide to the Ebenezer Johnson Papers 1919-1952
Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon Libraries
Ebenezer Johnson papers
1919-1952
Ax 659
Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon Libraries 1299 University of Oregon Eugene, Oregon, 97403-1299 (541) 346-3068 spcarref@uoregon.edu
1.5 linear feet 1 container
Collection comprises papers of American missionary Ebenezer S. Johnson, including correspondence; minutes of the Angola, Congo, and Rhodesia mission conferences; clippings and photographs of mission work.
1 container
Johnson, Ebenezer
Box 1
Biographical/Historical note
Ebenezer S. Johnson (b. 1866) was a missionary and bishop in the Methodist Episcopal Church, stationed in south and central Africa.
Collection comprises papers of American missionary Ebenezer S. Johnson, including correspondence; minutes of the Angola, Congo, and Rhodesia mission conferences; clippings and photographs of mission work.
Collection is organized into the following series:
Correspondence
Official records
Subject files
Pamphlets, clippings, maps, scrapbooks
Photographs
Collection is open to the public.
Collection must be used in Special Collections University Archives Reading Room.
Paper finding aid with additional information available in Special Collections University Archives.
Johnson, Ebenezer S.--Correspondence; Johnson, Ebenezer S.
Methodist Episcopal Church
Methodist Episcopal Church--Missions--Africa; Methodist Episcopal Church--Records and correspondence; Missionaries--Africa; Missions, American--Africa
Missionaries; Photographs; Religion
- Correspondence—Incoming, 1923-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence—Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Angola Mission Conference—Official journal, 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Congo Mission Conference—Manuscrips of journal of proceedings, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Congo Mission Conference—Manuscripts of journal of proceedings, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Congo—Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Rhodesia—Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Subject File: Bishop Johnson’s trip across Angola and the Belgian Congo, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Subject File: General Jan Christian Smuts Rhodes lectures, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Subject File: Race Relations—South Africa, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper clippings, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Maps—Africa, Belgian Congo, Congo Mission, Trade Routes (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Scrapbooks (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Angola, Photographs—unidentified (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Angola, Photographs—identified, Postcards—captioned (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Congo Belge, Photographs—unidentified (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Congo Belge, Photographs—identified, Postcards—captioned (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Rhodesia, Photographs—identified (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Rhodesia, Photographs—unidentified (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 3 photographs (Box 1)
- 7 miscellaneous Mission Conference publications (Box 1)